# Sara Sardar

# UI/UX Designer II Front-End Devlopment

sarasardar2777@gmail.com 0770 059-2777 Behance I <u>Dribble</u> LinkedIn I GitHub

Iraq-Erbil

Portfolio

# Education

# Salahaddin University - Bachelor degree

2012-2017

College of Engineering-Software Department

# **UXUI Design Bootcamp - Re:Coded**

Jul 2019 - Nov 2022

- Completing a 5-month immersive design bootcamp, with 300+ hours of curricula and project-based learning
- Topics include: Design Thinking, UX Research Methods, Interaction Design, Visual Design, User Interface Design, User Testing and Low/High-Fidelity Prototyping, etc...

### **UXUI Design Bootcamp - Wecode**

Jul 2019 - Nov 2022 Rwanga Foundation

- Completing a 3-month immersive design bootcamp, with 300+ hours of curricula and project-based learning
- Topics include: Design Thinking, UX Research Methods, Interaction Design, Visual Design, User Interface Design, User Testing and Low/High-Fidelity Prototyping, etc...

#### Front-End Development and Design Bootcamp - WeCoded

Jul 2019 - Sep 2021 Rwanga Foundation

- Completing a 3-month bootcamp, 39 technical pieces of training (3 hours each), 13-weeks of intensive learning (117 hours)
- Topics include: Framework (React, React-Dom, Links (Router), Axious, State, Tailwind, TailwindUi, Netlify, NPM, JSX, Boilerplate (CRA), components, Props, Events, Styling Component, ...etc.),
- Portfolio Responsive Project (Website, Mobile Application), Framework (Bootstrap), Web development (HTML5, CSS, JavaScript).

# languages

Kurdish: Naitive

English: Full Professional working proficiency

Arabic: Elementary proficiency

# Overview

I'm focused on creating meaningful experiences through design, and helping companies build great digital products. I have a passion for working with creative thinkers, leading brainstorming sessions, vetting ideas, and seeing them come to life in a way that delights users.

## Skills

Figma, Adobe XD, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, REACT, TAILWIND, NETLIFY, BOOTSTRAP, Canva, Canvas, Codepen

# Projects

### **Kurdlancer - UX/UI Designer case study**

Jul 2019 - Nov 2022

- Kurdlancer Responsive Project (Website, Mobile Application)
- Topics include: Design Thinking, UX Research Methods, Interaction Design, Visual Design, User Interface Design, User Testing and Low/High-Fidelity Prototyping, etc...

# Weride - UX/UI Designer case study

Jul 2022 - Nov 2022

- Weride ( Mobile Application
- Topics include: Design Thinking, UX Research Methods, Interaction Design, Visual Design, User Interface Design, User Testing and Low/ High-Fidelity Prototyping, etc...

### **Kurdlancer - Front-End Development (React)**

Jul 2019 - Sep 2021

- Kurdlancer Responsive Project (Website, Mobile Application)
- Framework (React, React-Dom, Links (Router), Axious, State, Tailwind, TailwindUi, Netlify, NPM, JSX, Boilerplate (CRA), components, Props, Events, Styling Component, ...etc.),
- Portfolio Responsive Project (Website, Mobile Application), Framework (Bootstrap), Web devlopment (HTML5, CSS, JavaScript)

#### Greeny - UX/UI Designer case study

Jul 2022 - Nov 2022

- Greeny Responsive Project (Website, Mobile Application).
- Topics include: Design Thinking, UX Research Methods, Interaction Design, Visual Design, User Interface Design, User Testing and Low/ High-Fidelity Prototyping, etc...

# Work Experience

### Axisxgroup Company / Talabk company

28/9/2023

- Worked as UX/UI Designer for TALABK project consist of (<u>Talabk User Application</u>, <u>Talabk Store Application</u>, <u>Talabk Website</u>, <u>Talabk Admin Dashboard</u>) for 4 months till previous time.
- Presenting all the projects of Talabk company to the visitors in Gravity Event at Erbil international fair 2023 for 3 days

#### High Performance Company /Talabat company

5/5/2023-9/7/2023

- Got 40 days training from Talabat company in advanced ways about how to solve riders problems in both theoretical and practical ways, practical part included shadowing, live tasking, how to work in teams, ...etc.
- Worked on multiple systems 9 hrs//5 days/week, handling inbound and outbound calls, emails, chats from riders, restaurants and customers, solved their problems according to the rules of Talabat Company which uses Dispatching Knowledge Base website, documenting each problem in the Okta system which included (Herocare, Hurrier, BOA (Back Office Application), DH).

#### **HITEX Exhibition Anual Fair**

2022

- HITEX 2022 was the meeting platform for the region's top tech businesses and a learning source for cutting-edge innovations.
- Representative of Ora application and website in Hitex Exhibition 2022 for 4 days, Presenting the Ora application to visitors, Ora is a Service application/website
- Presenting all the projects of Rwanga Foundation to the visitors in Hitex Exhibition 2021 for 4 days

## Software Engineering Department annual fair (Sedaf)

2012-2017

- Developed Ping Pong game with Sedaf annual fair at Salahaddin University.
- Camera security project with Sedaf annual fair at Salahaddin University.
- Developed CAD (continues academic development system) for QA (quality assurance) at salahaddin university.

### **Bring Hope Humanitarian Foundation**

2019-2020

- Preparing and sorting documents for data entry.
- Entering data into database software and checking to ensure the accuracy
  of the data that has been inputted
- Creating data backups as part of a contingency plan
- Responding to information requests from authorized members
- · Testing new database systems and software updates.

## Courses/Certifications

- -Certificate of completion (5 months, 86 Hours of Classes with the trainers, 50 Assignments submitted), of intensive UX/UI Design training bootcamp as a part of Re:coded.
- -Certificate of completion (3 monthes/12 weeks/114 hours) of intensive UX/UI training bootcamp as a part of WeCode project implemented by Rwanga Foundation.
- -Certificate of completion (3 monthes/12 weeks/117 hours) of intensive Front-End Devlopment and Design training bootcamp as a part of WeCode project implemented by Rwanga Foundation.
- -Certificate of completion ( 3 weeks) of intensive Intor to Freelancing training courses a part of Inspire series with Re:coded.
- -Child Protection Workshop at Bring Hope Humanitarian Foundation.
- -Computer skills (MS Word, Excel, PowerPoint and Access), Training Course at Ganjan Center.
- -Basic AutoCAD, Training Course at College of Engineering.
- -Human Resource Management with American corner Erbil platform in collaboration with WEDO Academy.
- -Digital Marketing Management with American corner Erbil platform in collaboration with WEDO Academy.
- -Human Resource (HR) Training Course at Top International Academy TIA.
- -CV Creation and Find jobs, Training Course at GMAC.
- -GSM Internship at Asia Cell Summer Program.

# Industry Knowledge

- · User Interface
- User Experience
- Product Design
- Project Design (Website/Application)
- Design Research
- Interaction Design
- API's (Get, Post)
- · Hooks ,Data Fetching in React
- MUI
- · Ant Design
- Bootstraps
- React, React-Dom
- Shadow/Virtual DOM
- Links (Router)
- Axious
- Boilerplate(CRA)
- JSX
- · Components, Props
- State
- Events
- Babel